WALSHE, R. CALEN

Visual & Computational Neuroscientist

CONTACT



calen.walshe@gmail.com



www.calenwalshe.com



calenwalshe



512-758-5373



Austin, TX







Cognitive Science

Bayesian Perception

Eye movements

Psychophysics

EEG

Signal Detection Theory

Signal Processing

Fourier Analysis

Image Quality Assessment

Data Science and Machine Learning

Maximum Likelihood Estimation Discriminant Analysis

Deep Learning

Reinforcement Learning

Bayesian Regression

Least Squares Regression

Logistic Regression

Generalized Linear Model

Bayesian Decision Theory

Bayesian Hierarchical Regression

Support Vector Machines

Monte Carlo Methods

Data Visualization

Software

Keras/TensorFlow

CUDA

Anaconda

ggplot/dplyr (tidyverse)

Eyelink

Linux

LaTeX

Google Cloud Services

Psychtoolbox Google G Suite

Adobe Creative Suite

Programming

MATLAB

Python

Markdown

HTML/CSS

SOL

ABOUT MF

My work as a scientist has taken me in many directions that all have a common theme: to understand how the brain converts visual perception into intelligent action. The primary set of methods that I use in my research combines behavioral experiments and machine learning. The goal of the work is to develop algorithms that solve perceptual tasks such as object recognition and visual search in similar ways to humans. In basic research I have consistently delivered on funding awards by generating peer reviewed scientific publications, giving talks and presenting conference posters. In my work as an applied scientist I have helped stakeholders identify key insights for business and product development. Please don't hesitate to get in touch if you would like to know more about my background

WORK EXPERIENCE



Institute for Neuroscience Center for Perceptual Systems, The University of Texas at Austin, USA.

Postdoctoral Researcher | August 2015 - Present

- Developed signal processing models of the human retina
- Developed machine learning algorithms to detect objects in natural scenes
- Conducted eye tracking and psychophysical experiments on human subjects
- Used deep learning methods to imitate human actions in game play
- Customized computer vision tools to process large scale image datasets





ENQUIRO Accelerate Internship, Enquiro Search Solutions, Vancouver, Canada.

Research Intern | September 2009 – September 2010

- · Worked with stakeholders to identify key research objectives and potential value
- · Worked with a clinical population to measure neural correlates of brand preferences via EEG methods
- Generated written reports that guided future product design and business development

EDUCATION



The University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, Scotland

Ph.D. in Psychology, Cognitive Neuroscience | Sept 2011 - May 2015

- Developed state of the art algorithms to detect rapid eye movements with low error
- Applied machine learning techniques to predict human eye movement behavior
- Taught courses in R programming and advanced statistics
- Awarded competitive scholarships totaling \$120,000 over four years

SFU Simon Fraser University, Burnaby, BC, Canada

B.A. in Cognitive Science | Jan 2005 - Feb 2009

- Applied machine learning methods to predict human eye movements
- Measured human behavior in eye tracking studies
- Measured neural activity in human subjects using EEG methods
- Prepared exams and invigilated exams for 8 courses over 2 years as a TA

ACADEMIC CONTRIBUTIONS

- Walshe, R. C., & Geisler, W. S. Detection of occluding targets in natural scenes. (Under Review at Journal of Vision)
- Ruohan, Z., Walshe, R.C. et al. (2019). Atari-HEAD: Atari human eye-tracking and demonstration dataset. preprint arXiv. arXiv:1903.06754 (Paper presented at AAAI'20).
- Walshe, R. C., Sebastian, S., & Geisler, W. (2018). Ideal observer for detection of occluding targets in natural scenes in the fovea and periphery. Journal of Vision, 18(10), 629-629.
- Walshe, R.C. & Nuthmann, A. (2015). Mechanisms of saccadic decision making while encoding naturalistic scenes.
- Walshe, R.C. & Nuthmann, A. (2014). Asymmetric control of fixation durations in scene viewing. Vision Research, 100, 38-46.

